<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-17T00:01:25+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Blog || iiqrah</title><subtitle>YouTube &amp;middot; iOS Development &amp;middot; Digital Art</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Friendship on a pedestal.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/friendship-on-a-pedestal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Friendship on a pedestal." /><published>2020-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/friendship-on-a-pedestal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/friendship-on-a-pedestal/">&lt;p&gt;A recent crush on a school friend made me write this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t think you happen to notice but it’s been a long time since I published a story.
No real reason other than my mind being very scattered which has resulted in many half finished story drafts that I predict will remain unfinished for a long time because I have outgrown my trail of thought about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anywho, today I want to write out my perspective on friendship.
Why friendship in particular you may ask, or rather I force you to ask?
Because only yesterday I came to the realisation that I have no friends, or rather feel like I have no friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a completely unrelated note, I used to confuse the spelling of friends, did not know if the i or the e came first, the song Friends by Anne-Marie and Marshmello has really helped with that. If you know, you know, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CY8E6N5Nzec&quot;&gt;else find out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not that I just happen to have a voilà moment yesterday, where I went “Voilà! I think I have no friends.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feeling has always existed but only yesterday while speaking to a school friend about my long obnoxious history of having too many short-lived crushes and trying to find the reason for it is when I realised it could be because I don’t have a tight group of friends, especially after high-school here in a new country that I moved to for university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that he has noticed, that unlike others, I don’t seem to have a group of friends that I hang out with. And this may not be a bad thing but it could be the reason why whenever I get comfortable enough to talk to someone new, I develop a short-lived crush on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think regardless of whether I would like to have a group of friends to hang out with or not, this particular observation does make sense and could be very well the reason why I have far few friends and much many crushes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am aware that all this could be complete bogus, but at the very least it was a catalyst to help me introspect more about the way I look at friendship and ponder as to why I skip straight to crushes rather than just have those new people become my friends instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since moving here, it’s been over 3 years now, I have met and interacted with a lot of people. There are way too many pre-strangers that are now active acquaintances or some-bodies that I used to know, but it is borderline discomforting for me to refer to, most if not, all of them to be my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A part of me thinks that if I were to have not know of the existence of the word acquaintance, I could potentially have way more friends without changing a single thing in my life at this given moment, but maybe not. Let me delve upon that some other day, it is not like I would ever know for sure because that’s just how things are with most “what if” scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, I have asked people how they come to the realisation that a certain someone is their friend. I have gotten varied answers and sometimes weird concerning looks because of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some don’t put any thought into it at all, “it just happens naturally”. For some, just knowing a bit more about someone, other than their name, is enough to call them their friend and there are some that have people that they grew up with or happen to share loads with which has made them feel comfortable enough to call those people their friend. Oh, and there are some people that think they have no friends.
Now this was really interesting to me because it made me realise that often times than not I tend to meet a new person, talk to them and if we “click”, I rather have them assigned the label of an acquaintance or a crush, depending on certain other characteristics, than simply just a friend which is ridiculous but that is just what I tend to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not sure why but I have a very high regard when it comes to friendship, almost as if I put &lt;em&gt;friendship on a pedestal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the possibilities could be that I consider a friend to be someone that I can be truly vulnerable in front of, someone I can completely trust and hope to never hurt or get hurt by. It is a pretty big ask which I don’t expect most people to fulfil. By categorising them as acquaintance, they don’t have to abide by any of my high standards and by being a crush it is more of a one-sided relationship at least from my eyes so that gives me the option to get hurt by them through future interactions and not feel bad about it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if any of this makes any sense. I don’t think any of this is worth even reading. I feel a strong urge to apologise to you if you happened to reach till this point. I’m sorry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems like an unfinished story to me because I do not want to introduce a turning point and be like “Voilà! I think I am going to have friends.” because whatever I have shared right now about my perspective on friendship is something I standby. It is just that I wasn’t as hyper aware about it until I tried analysing my reasons for having so many crushes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also aware that I am considered to be a friend by more people than the number of people I consider my friend. I am also open to the idea that there are and would be people that I consider friends who might not consider me their friend.
No one passed on the guide to me about friendship so not really sure about the rights and wrongs or the do’s and don’ts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe in a few year’s time or sooner all this wouldn’t make any sense to me either. But I am not too bothered by that because I am sure to outgrow my current outlook of the world, or rather to hope to outgrow my current outlook of the world, I have to experience more of life, friendship and perception.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random Thoughts" /><category term="random thoughts" /><summary type="html">A recent crush on a school friend made me write this post.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The blame game in society.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/the-blame-game-in-society/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The blame game in society." /><published>2019-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/the-blame-game-in-society</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/the-blame-game-in-society/">&lt;p&gt;The situation with GitHub and US sanction trade laws made me feel the need to write this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am deeply saddened and disgusted by what I came across my newsfeed right now about Iranians and citizens of a few other countries losing access to their GitHub benefits because of some US sanction trade laws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get the frustration of millions of developers and GitHub users, their instinct to blame the company and the CEO. They are doing what any emotional human being would do, try to find an entity to blame for their suffering, even though GitHub is merely following laws issued by the US government. I have done a really dangerous thing here. By making that statement alone, I have contributed to this blind mindless blame game of pointing fingers at the government instead of the company, which probably roots from my personal preferential biases for GitHub and my ignorant uninformed understanding of the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is extremely easy for me to cater to my biases and shift the blame on the ruthless decisions of the government, but I truly took no effort into understanding the reasoning behind these laws. And to be completely honest, I do not even think I will, probably because I do not care enough? And it is much easier to just find an entity you dislike, connect it to the problem and blame it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often times I let me thinker personality run wild. I am left pondering as to how we have let the society embody the principles that it has today, and if it would be different in case another set of humans would be responsible for building the early stages, but that is as pointless as thinking what if &lt;strong&gt;insert literally anything&lt;/strong&gt;, and for all I know, it could turn out to be worse than what it is right now. What ifs are a pointless time-wasting thought process to be in unless they are directed towards something that can actually be changed and have a purpose, for the good or bad, behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I know, and I am completely aware that I could be wrong, but all I know is I can not help in any way or make a difference, at least not a substantial one. So all I choose to do is briefly get affected by it, rant about it through my cluttered and disorganized writing and then go on living my unaffected life. It is such a privileged curse to feel so helpless about making this world a better place because I lack the first-hand suffering of these atrocities that happen in our society, which lets my self-loathing narcissistic self think that, perhaps, I could be the one to be blamed for all of the sufferings in the world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random Thoughts" /><category term="random thoughts" /><summary type="html">The situation with GitHub and US sanction trade laws made me feel the need to write this post.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The dilemma between power and peace.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/the-dilemma-between-power-and-peace/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The dilemma between power and peace." /><published>2019-06-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-06-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/the-dilemma-between-power-and-peace</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/the-dilemma-between-power-and-peace/">&lt;p&gt;The situation in Sudan currently has made me feel the need to write this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been doing a pretty great job of being ignorant about the problems going on in this world lately. And after having experienced it myself, I do agree, ignorance is bliss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was too occupied complaining about not having enough will to eat healthy, or getting more sleep than I need, and the worst problem of all of not having a partner that I can love and confide to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was almost like I was not even conscious of the people of this world scattered around the globe that are dying out of hunger and thirst, some cannot get sleep for more than a few seconds because of the loud noises coming from gun fires, and those same gun fires depriving them of their loved ones till eternity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This facade was broken a few minutes back when I decided to tap on a friends Instagram story. It gave me a crash course on the things happening in Sudan as of now. The same old same old people killing and hurting others while battling within themselves to find the right balance between power and peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans seem to be hungry for power and peace, and the saddest, most ironical part is that both of these things are at the opposite sides of the spectrum. To gain power, you have to let go of peace, regardless of trying to convince yourself that it is only for a brief moment. And the same applies to restoring peace. It is this constant dilemma between power and peace that has and will destroy nations universally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But interestingly enough, this is not exclusive only to governments and leaders. Our parents have the same dilemma, a little spanking or shouting could go a long way at establishing the authoritative power in the house and maybe even a delusional peaceful environment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the same dilemma can be seen for an individual battling with their own life decisions. We could give up our peace by taking up power to do something about these “unjust”(I put unjust in quotes because we all are biased in all situations no matter what, and maybe from our perception it is clear that it is unjust but from the people that make the decision to kill, they probably have justifications for their actions in great lengths, but bias is a topic for another day) wars. Or we could just give up our power, and lead an ignorant peaceful life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And suppose for a second I do decide to choose power and take action. What actions do I take that can actually help? Which battles and wars do I pick to take actions for? Is putting up an Instagram story or writing a Medium post enough of an action?
I’ve heard this saying a couple of times that goes something like “The only thing necessary for the triumph of evil is that good men do nothing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is just doing something or anything by good men enough for evil to not triumph? I somewhat get the idea behind this quote, but what exactly do good men do? And how do we even know if we are the good or the evil in a situation? Is the only way to find out which side is right is by seeing where the majority of mass killing is being taken place? Is that the metric that needs to be followed? Or is there a way for good men to do something before evil triumphs, but what if those decisions are that make them the evil that triumphs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I am looking at this from a completely wrong perspective, I really do not know. The more I try to learn, the more I find out the less I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So then by the process of elimination, do I pick peace over power and knowingly live an ignorantly blissful life?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random Thoughts" /><category term="random thoughts" /><summary type="html">The situation in Sudan currently has made me feel the need to write this post.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Muddled Thoughts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/muddled-thoughts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Muddled Thoughts" /><published>2019-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/muddled-thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/muddled-thoughts/">&lt;p&gt;Presenting to you a bunch of thoughts that go through my head, time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am not good enough”, “taking the first job offer might be a regret”, “I failed so many coding interviews, I am worthless”, “the company that made the offer should not have, what if I negatively affect the company’s progress”, “why did they offer me the job, they should have picked someone else”, “I am not clever, just really good at pretending to be”, “I feel like a self-aware imposter hiding behind imposter syndrome”, “I want to brag about the activities I do on social media, but why should I?”, “Validating my work through social media brag seems cringey but also is it depriving me of opportunities?”, “I do not deserve the opportunities I get”, “what do I want to achieve from my life”, “i really do not want to get too caught up living an ordinary life that revolves only around a mediocre job and family but I am not so gutsy to take risks in life and will be stuck in the generic construct of how this society was build by our ancestors”, “humans are such refined creatures, why do the majority of us are too afraid to experiment and test our limits”, “I have taken part in so many events/workshops outside uni but I still feel like I know nothing”, “I felt quite accomplished completing the MMU cheese app today with no help from anyone, StackOverflow not counted”, “I should have a portfolio as a CS student but I am too lazy to create one”, “Most of the time I enjoy planning events/workshops more than actually attending them”, “have I taken the wrong course? but I do love CS, even though I think I am not smart enough for it”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBC …&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random Thoughts" /><category term="random thoughts" /><summary type="html">Presenting to you a bunch of thoughts that go through my head, time to time.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My first failed suicide attempt.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/my-first-failed-suicide-attempt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My first failed suicide attempt." /><published>2019-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/my-first-failed-suicide-attempt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/my-first-failed-suicide-attempt/">&lt;p&gt;I am in a really dark place and I need to vent out my emotions, it is too much to handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi there, Iqrah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing this, so obviously I did not follow through. Unless I stop midway of writing this and just go ahead and do the deed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I know I won’t. I really don’t have the guts to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is weird because I have never felt this way before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t even know why I woke up today with such a strong urge to want to kill myself, even though I know I won’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So obviously, the next logical thing I did was google “suicide”. A helpline for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=suicide&amp;amp;oq=suicide&amp;amp;aqs=chrome.0.69i59j46l2j0l2j69i60l3.1221j0j9&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;Samaritans&lt;/a&gt; came up. But I am really not the kind of person that likes phone calls, that would lead to more stress and anxiety, so it is kind of ironic how that was the first thing that was recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially because my online presence is being tracked so efficiently, the least they can do is provide me with a customized suicide prevention strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never have I ever received an ad for Always Sanitary napkins, but on the day of my period, voila! the first ad I see on YouTube is an Always Sanitary pad ad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So then I clicked on the NHS resource, 90% of it was advising me to just talk to someone, the same advice written in 10 different ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I did not know what to talk to or who to talk to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am really good at unloading irrelevant baggage on some of my friends but when it comes to things like killing myself, I really don’t want them to get worried unnecessarily, especially because I don’t have it in me to follow through, so it is kind of a wasted effort on their side to be all emotional and convince me about how much I mean to them etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I did choose a random friend and decided to try and talk about it, but his advice was to “talk to a professional”, “get professional help” etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he was talking from “personal experience”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in my head, I was just like “Wow wtf, is this some sort of hierarchal procedure of referring to one person/institution after the other and get to talk to as many people as you possibly can” but talking is not my strongest suit so I am doomed before I can even begin to unravel this for myself? Guess that leaves me with the only option that is killing myself? Which again I won’t do, so am I just supposed to sit here in my flat, balling my eyes out due to my incapability of seeking help or going through with the plan? What a great first world problem to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to search suicide + my university’s name, and the article that showed up was about this guy who I was in foundational year with, and the title said “Student who self-harmed was given 10 minutes with university counsellor before taking his life a day later”, so talking does not really work always, does it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also felt a strong urge to tell my parents that I miss them. I HAVE NEVER DONE THAT BEFORE. But it was nice to let them know that I actually do love and miss them.
My next Google search was trying to find live footage of suicide attempts, just trying to figure out how do people do it and how long it takes. If I would have dug deeper I guess I would find more options. But all I could find were gunshots, and I don’t possess a gun so I cannot really use that methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it was amusing to see how fast everything ends. Or at least it appears to. No one other than that person can tell you if it actually is as painless as it appears to be.
But after dwelling for quite some time on this topic, I was calmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the span of my research, I was also chatting with a few other people about different things. One friend was trying to explain how weird he felt waking up from a vivid dream, I was also trying to help another friend with her love life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No idea how but this vivid dream conversation segued into me light-heartedly talking about my research and what I was feeling. He thought I was joking at first, but even when he realized I wasn’t, he kept the banter going which was kind of nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like joking about death, even when my life or my loved one’s life is at stake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But yeah, the conversation was really helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conveniently enough, my mom also saw the message around the same time, which led her to get worried. Stupid me. So she called.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked. At first, she thought it had something to do with guys and relationship problems, but talking to her made me realize it was just my stress related to the hackathon that I am organizing. The planning has been going on for the last six months, and it has emotionally and physically drained me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems quite trivial but I feel this immense pressure of disappointing everyone involved, or things not going according to plan, two weeks left and things are already falling apart, so idk, it felt easier to run away from this commitment and end this constant stress. I could not even do my programming assignment to my fullest capability because of this hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I really cannot end my life. I want to do so much good in this world, make a difference, so I really don’t think that the world would be a better place without me sticking around until I am “destined” to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not really have an exceptional artistic talent that can sway the world like Freddie Mercury did, but at least I would like to make an effort into making this world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my mom advised me to get out of my bed, take a bath and deal with one issue at a time, related to this hackathon. And that is what I tried doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replied to a bunch of e-mails. Made a few phone calls. None made any real progress because e-mails are such an inefficient way of communication and financial transactions take so long, and to make matters worse, you have zero to no control over both of them so you’re just left hanging helplessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But bathing really helped. Idk why but it did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late evening I caught up with another friend that I had sort of distanced myself from for a long time. It was hard not crying in front of him, stupid me. But it was cool.
Rest of the day I was just conversing with that vivid dreamer friend. He suggested I watch my first twitch stream: Asmongold Welfare Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the troll videos that he was paid to watch were genuinely hilarious.
But midway I just dozed off and had the best peaceful sleep in a really long time. But my sleep schedule is totally messed up now. I have also made the wrong decision of drinking coffee, so I am wide awake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the back of my mind, I am still thinking about loads of things that need to be done for the hackathon. And I only have 10 days left to complete it all.
But I am going to quote my friend here to remind me “a hackathon is not worth a life especially one that has a good future”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think my last search of the day is “does it hurt to cut your wrist”, some really insightful answers on Quora. Getting really tired of this samaritan helpline that I am being suggested in all suicide-related searches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly though, I would rather kill myself than engage in a phone call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But re-reading whatever I wrote till now is making me realize how talking did help. I did not intend to talk but somehow organically it happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypocrisy at it’s finest. Makes me a self-aware hypocrite which in my opinion is worse.
But that’s all from me for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, if I am alive after the 27th, I’ll update about how the hackathon actually went, or if it even happened or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adios.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random Thoughts" /><category term="random thoughts" /><category term="suicide" /><summary type="html">I am in a really dark place and I need to vent out my emotions, it is too much to handle.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An immense hope in hopelessness.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/an-immense-hope-in-hopelessness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An immense hope in hopelessness." /><published>2018-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/an-immense-hope-in-hopelessness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/an-immense-hope-in-hopelessness/">&lt;p&gt;I feel extremely hopeless so I need to vent out my thoughts and come to terms with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi there, no one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time since I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrong priorities like university took over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before starting this post, I had a read on the other three that I published and I have come to the realization that I have shared an uncomfortable amount of my personal life. I could have just made an anonymous account, but we are too deep into this already, besides why should only Facebook have the right to get a sneak peek into my personal life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am fully aware of how messy my digital footprint is at the moment, but I cannot even get myself to untangle my earphone wires, let alone cleanse my digital data. We are all going to die soon anyway. None of this would matter then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I wanted to write this post ranting and venting out my current feelings about university and the education system as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a few days now, I was finding it really hard to understand why I am enrolled at a university and willingly wasting time not doing anything constructive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a bit of pondering to realize that the reason I joined uni in the first place was purely because of my interest in the subject that I developed in high school. I wanted to explore this field further, not realizing uni life is all about finding a high paying job offer and getting good grades in your exams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I joined uni, I haven’t experienced the kind of mental growth I was hoping for. A lot of the content is not presented in a way that allows me to quench my thirst for exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was becoming a little frustrating to know that I allowed my younger, dumber, naive Iqrah to decide the course my future will be taking. But then again, considering I haven’t really grown that much, I am still quite similar to that Iqrah, so I hold no grudges against her. She took the best decision she could, considering the situation and limited knowledge she had (and has).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not want to sound completely ungrateful, a lot of good things have come from being at uni. But pure academic-wise, I haven’t found it challenging enough. It is annoying to be spoon-fed chunks of new coding paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then again, I do not think I am smart enough to figure out these paradigms on my own, but ain’t that the reason why I enrolled myself at university? To be taught in an understanding manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t aware that I will be spending a huge amount of money merely to get a piece of paper that supposedly declares me qualified to attain the knowledge in a subject I decided to pursue, even though deep down I know, the information disappeared from my brain the moment I closed my pen cap or switched of my pc I was attempting my exam on.
So yeah, all this was making me feel quite helpless. The next logical thought was to end this “misery” (being a little bit too dramatic here) and not waste any more time and cash on this pointless endeavour, aka drop out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But additional to being not too smart or knowledgeable, I am also very gutless. And dropping out from something right away takes a lot of courage which I am deprived of currently. Drastic change requires guts, and I am too comfortable in my student accommodation sofa right now to give up this comforting and known environment. I would rather just rant about it in a post than take actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this realization and this feeling of hopelessness did make me reach out to people and ask them about their aspirations and dreams, their reasoning of why they are doing what they are doing, why they want to do what they want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side note: these conversations were quite intriguing and have sparked a new curiosity in me to find out more about the reasoning behind decisions people make. It is being a bit too nosey, but some humans love sharing their personal lives without having a care in the world, often times to another human being and the other times online, maybe on a medium post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after having these conversations, I still felt quite hopeless about myself.
Whenever I have found myself in a hopeless situation, I write my thoughts out.
So that is what I did, last night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not here, but in my physical personal diary. And while I was ranting away my frustration and hopelessness, I came to a marvellous realization, which is what I wanted to capture in this post because, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=google+translate+%D9%84%D8%A7+%D8%B3%D9%85%D8%AD+%D8%A7%D9%84%D9%84%D9%87&amp;amp;oq=google+translate+%D9%84%D8%A7+%D8%B3%D9%85%D8%AD+%D8%A7%D9%84%D9%84%D9%87&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j69i64j69i60l3.422j0j4&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;la samah allah&lt;/a&gt;, my diary drowns before my life comes to an end, I will still be able to access my forgotten thoughts here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what I realized is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I do drop out, then what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I haven’t figured out the latter, then why drop out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I do figure out what I want to do with my life, why not just do it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless staying at uni would hinder my aspirations, I could just get on with making my life useful without necessarily having to drop out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made total sense to me. And made me realize that the flawed educational system is not entirely to be blamed for my hopelessness. I am equally to be blamed too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I want to explore more about the subject that I am interested in, no one is stopping me from doing it except for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I want to make a difference in this world, even though I have no idea how to, no one is stopping me from figuring out how except for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out Shia LaBeouf did know what he was talking about. There was more to it than just meme-ing it in inappropriate contexts. For the first time ever, watching that video gave me goosebumps, along with the prevalent laughter because it is still way too much emotion for me to take it seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I would like to believe that this realization brings a lot more hope in my hopelessness. The awareness also brings along a lot more responsibility as I can no longer blame anyone else other than myself for not doing what I want to do or at least trying to figure out what I want to do and then trying to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll keep you posted about how I failed (or did not fail) at turning things around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless, of course, I drown to death before I get to write my update.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random Thoughts" /><category term="random thoughts" /><category term="hopelessness" /><summary type="html">I feel extremely hopeless so I need to vent out my thoughts and come to terms with it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Death</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/death/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Death" /><published>2018-08-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/death</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/death/">&lt;p&gt;I feel like discussing the way I view death and share my thought on losing someone who was more than an acquaintance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I am someone who enjoys inappropriate humour, specially the ones revolving around death. Hardly ever a day goes by, without me mentioning death in a casual or comedic sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not sure if this is right or wrong, besides there is nothing as straightforward as right or wrong, absolutely nothing, not even murder.
And often times I wonder what the reason might me for me to take death so casually, and not just limiting it to my friends but also mentioning it to my parents, grandparents and whoever I deem close to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it is because I haven’t really experienced losing someone who is deeply close to me. But that is partially untrue. I did lose a friend at the beginning of this year. Someone who I had a wonderful conversation with face to face, laughing about trivial things in life, at the New Year’s Eve party, and he was just gone forever after 3 days.
I haven’t really been able to speak about it properly to anyone, mostly because I was not BFFs with this person but also not just acquaintance. And I seem to put all my friends in those two categories, so I wasn’t sure if my reaction or the things that I wanted to speak about would matter or be appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t BFFs with him, so it did not really hit me that hard, but it did somehow make me uneasy to an extreme amount and made my eyes shed tears uncontrollably (for a few days after which I was completely fine).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I was not just acquaintance with him, I was definitely more than that, so I badly wanted the news to just be a sick “my-kinda-humour” prank and be able to meet this person again in the following vacations to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And somehow this also makes me feel really selfish because it feels like I am making this all about me. But so be it because I really want all this off my chest.
I don’t know where I going with this. After his death I did feel some sort of a new sense of frustration and grief that I had never felt before, which made me sort of push away someone from my life that I had become really close to recently around that time, but at the same time I still joke about death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thought of my bffs and parents dying has crossed my mind as well, but even that does not make me stop taking death so casually and comedically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, for one, am not afraid of death. I am afraid of drowning which is why I have a strong feeling that is how I am destined to die. But I am not afraid of death. I would love to be dead. Everyone does have to die one day or the other, even if they decide to freeze their body now and wake up (or not) after a few centuries when the cure for cancer is discovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also certain that once a person is dead, the person is dead, so it doesn’t really matter to the person after they are dead. It is only when you are alive or experience someone else dying, that brings about emotions of worrisome and the want to not die, which is understandable, relatable and ridiculous to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why worry about things that are certain, wouldn’t it be more logical to think about things that are not certain? Such as life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not sure what the point of writing all this was, seems like it was more for reassuring myself of why I think of death the way I do and even at times (like right now) when I get reminded of the person (or more people to get added to the list as time passes by) that is no longer with me and the kind of frustration and uneasiness it brings along, it is all sort of a coping mechanism. Because one other thing certain and beautiful as death is time, with the contrast difference of death having the absence of healing and time being the ultimate embodiment of healing. Our hearts, our mind, our soul, anything can be healed with time, we just need to consciously give time to time, unless death races time to it and we all die without the much needed time we longed for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wish everyone reading this a peaceful death.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random Thoughts" /><category term="random thoughts" /><category term="death" /><summary type="html">I feel like discussing the way I view death and share my thought on losing someone who was more than an acquaintance.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My First Ever (Online) Write-Up</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/my-first-ever-online-write-up/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My First Ever (Online) Write-Up" /><published>2018-08-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/my-first-ever-online-write-up</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/random%20thoughts/my-first-ever-online-write-up/">&lt;p&gt;This is me trying to write my first online, public facing write-up for the world to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feels so weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never really dared to experiment with this realm of writing and posting my thoughts online for anyone to take a sneak peek at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not that I am not comfortable with this, but I definitely feel weird.
Weird: a word in the English language that helps me describe a feeling whenever I lack the knowledge of a better word to describe the feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a second thought, let me actually Google the word to find the official meaning of it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=weird+meaning&amp;amp;oq=weird+meaning&amp;amp;aqs=chrome.0.69i59j0l6j69i60.2042j1j9&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;Meaning of weird&lt;/a&gt;.That is extremely intriguing to me, at least the Scottish and archaic meaning: “a person’s destiny”. Never really thought it had any connection with destiny or fate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But oh well, here I am typing away my abrupt and unplanned thoughts at 10:41 pm (Qatar time, (ooops is that too much personal information to give out about myself? The advertisers probably already know that and have probably shoved me into a target audience that resides in Qatar, so I guess it does not matter.)) in my room, without having any intention of doing so, so in a way feeling weird does seem appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have completely lost track of why I even began to write, and this post just seems like it’s turning into a post about weird, which is why I am going to start bold-ing (is that even a word? at least for now it is) the word weird so that I can count how many times I used it in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right, so going back to a previous thought about how anyone would be able to get a sneak peak of my brain dump, I think that’s the top-most contributing factor to why I feel weird. But then again, I highly doubt anyone would search for the title that I have given this post, and having no followers would help, if not no one else, then at least very limited amount of people to discover this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, I am aware of other services where you are able to write without having to post it publicly, but that seems similar to writing in my diary, that I have done for a very long time since I acquired the skill to form thoughts and sentences.
I obviously wasn’t consistent enough to write every single day of my life but often enough to have captured all kinds of emotions and note-worthy memories, not all the note-worthy memories, but enough to make me nostalgic and proud to have been able to capture them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, I wanted to try something new for a change, and this seems exciting, weird but exciting, so I shall give this a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I am done for today, the green Publish button in this all B&amp;amp;W themed interface is calling for me. Love the aesthetics of this GUI btw, after-all B&amp;amp;W is my all time favourite colour combination. Ah, great! Let the B&amp;amp;W coloured product advertisements commence.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random Thoughts" /><category term="random thoughts" /><summary type="html">This is me trying to write my first online, public facing write-up for the world to see.</summary></entry></feed>